Professor Joseph Werlin Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Professor Joseph Werlin Papers
1942-1964
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Werlin, Joseph Sidney, 1900-1964
11.00 Linear Feet
The Professor Joseph S. Werlin Papers contain extensive newspaper and magazine articles relating to international issues of interest to Dr. Werlin. Topics include, but are not limited to, politics, racism, nationalism, agriculture, birth control, and many others. Most of the materials date from the 1940s and 1950s, there is also a limited amount of personal material, including correspondence and photographs, in the collection.
1971-004
Biographical Note
Professor Joseph S. Werlin was a charter member of the University of Houston faculty, having joined the Division of Social Sciences when the University was founded in 1934. He served the University with distinction and enthusiasm for 30 years.
As a man of many scholarly interests and accomplishments, Dr. Werlin was widely known as the founder and director of the University of Houston International Studies Center, and conducted educational tours for students to Latin America and Europe for over 19 years. Dr. Werlin's efforts toward furthering knowledge and understanding of the Latin American peoples and their cultures were recognized not only in the academic world but also by the governments of both Mexico and Guatemala.
Scope and Contents
The Professor Joseph S. Werlin Papers contain extensive newspaper and magazine articles relating to international issues of interest to Dr. Werlin. Topics include, but are not limited to, politics, racism, nationalism, agriculture, birth control, and many others. Most of the materials date from the 1940s and 1950s, there is also a limited amount of personal material, including correspondence and photographs, in the collection.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Arrangement of Materials
The collection arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. For preservation and access reasons, the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible including the vernacular of the period. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. Latin American Studies Program
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings; Correspondence; Photographs
Personal Name:
Werlin, Joseph Sidney, 1900-1964
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- University of Houston Files
  This series consists of three folders related to Professor Werlin's various activities at the University of Houston.
  - University of Houston - General Faculty Matters, 1934-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - University of Houston - General Faculty Matters, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Houston - Sociology Department Matters, 1953-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence
  This series contains twenty-one folders of correspondence between Dr. Werlin and various family members. Included in this section are also a limited number of family photographs. The folders have been arranged in chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Personal Photographs (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Speeches
  This series contains eleven dated speeches and sixteen undated speeches given by Professor Werlin between the years 1934 and 1942. This series is divided into two sub-series the first is arranged chronologically by date of the speech. The second set of speeches was not dated and thus was arranged alphabetically.
  - Our Changing World, August 26, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Difficulties in the Way of Producing a Cultured Generatic, November 7, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Emergency Peace Conference, April 30, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Points and Questions Regarding Minority Parties, November 8, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Reorganization of the Supreme Court: Why I am..., February 22, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Werlin Speeches :"Shall We Build Our Military.. .", February 27, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Suggested Topics for the Wednesday Morning Discussion Group, Oct. 16, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Pending Joust for Power, February 18, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Economics and Present troubles of the World, April 10, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Our Troubled World", July 26, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - How the War will Affect American Life, March 29, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Undated Speeches
    - A Four Point Peace Program - n.d (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Debate for Areas of Our cities - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Did England Betray the World - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Has the Dies Investigation Committee Justified Itself - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - How Can the United States best contribute to World Peace- n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - How Shall the Jews of Germany be Saved - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - How Should the Jews of America Proceed... - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Nationalism Old and New - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Parenthood in a Flaming World - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Shall America be Strongly Armed? - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Should Texas Pass a Sales Tax? - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - The Future of Unemployment and Relief - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - The Method in Russia's Madness - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Universities and the Royal Road - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - What America Can Learn From Everyone's Troubles - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - What is Greece to Me or I to Greece - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Subject Files
  This series contains forty-four folders dating from 1942 - 1954, arranged alphabetically. Included in this series are notes, correspondence relating to international study abroad opportunities at various universities including Cuba, Guatemala, and Mexico.
  - Addresses (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Addresses - Notes Texts (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Addresses - Notes Texts (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Addresses - Notes Texts (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - American Sociological Society (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Anecdotes: Jokes, stories, etc… (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence: Scholarships to French Students, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Cuba: Correspondence, University of Havana, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cuba: General Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Cuba: General Correspondence and Materials, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Cuba: General Information - Hotels, Transportation, Tr. Folders., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Cuba: General Information Publicity, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Cuba: Members, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Guatemala: General Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Guatemala: General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Guatemala: General Information - Articles, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Guatemala: Programs, Budgets, and Publicity, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Guatemala: Programs, Budgets, Publicity, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Fulbright Scholarships (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Mexico: Applications, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mexico: General Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mexico: General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mexico: General Information Publicity, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mexico: Programs, Budgets Publicity (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mexico: Programs, Budgets Publicity (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Plans, Data, Estimates…etc… (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Project: College Years in Mexico - Dr. Van Riper (Benjamin W) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, Meetings, etc, 1942-1944 -1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Summer Center Correspondence, 1943 -1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Summer Center Correspondence, 1944 -1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Summer Center General Correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Summer Centers: Publicity, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Summer Centers: Publicity, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Summer Centers: Programs, Budgets and Memoranda I (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University of Guatemala (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Class Lecture Materials
  This series contains seventy-four folders of newspaper articles and other research materials used by Professor Werlin for his classes. The sub-series is arranged by the course number, with the original folders titles maintained including the vernacular of the period. The newspaper articles cover a wide variety of topics including: education, religion, races, urbanization, birth control, old age, among many others. These materials relate to Professor Werlin's Sociology courses 231 to 573.
  - Soc 231: General (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Soc 231: History (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Soc 222: Negroes - Urban Situation (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Soc 231: Old Notes (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Soc 231: Progress (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Soc 231: Religion (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Soc 232: Education (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Soc 232: Introduction (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Soc 232: Negro: Voting Discrimination (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Soc 232: Old Age (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Soc 232: Social Security (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Soc 331: Africa Economy (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Soc 331: Birth Control (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Soc 331: Fish Algae Other Water Food (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Soc 331: Immigration (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Soc 331: Industry Trade (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Soc 331: Internationalism Binder III (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Soc 331: Over-population Situations (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Soc 331: Population (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Soc 331: Races - Eugenics (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Soc 331: Race Nationality (Non-Negro) US (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Soc 333: Housing (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Soc 333: Miscellaneous Material (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Soc 333: Negroes (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Soc 333: Parks and Recreation (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Soc 333: Shanghai (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Soc 333: Traffic (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Soc 333: The Urbanization of The United States (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Soc 334: Capitalism: Criticism of Capitalism (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Soc 334: Capitalism: Defense of Capitalism (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Soc 334: Communism (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Soc 334: Communism: China Asia (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Soc 334: Communism: Eastern Europe (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Soc 334: Communism: General (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Soc 334: Communism: USSR Communism Bloc States in Europe. Economic: Industrial Agricultural. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Soc 334: Communism: USSR - Political (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Soc 334: Communism: USSR - Western Europe (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Soc 334: Internationalism (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Soc 334: Internationalism - Political, Economic, Scientific, Cultural (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Soc 334: Political Democracy (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Soc 334: Socialism (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Soc 334: Socialism in Sweden (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Soc 335: Crime Treatment: Prevention (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Soc 335: Nature And Procedures (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Soc 415: USSR - As World Leader Power (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Soc 432: Child Labor (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Soc 432: Juvenile Delinquency: Control And Prevention (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Soc 432: Juvenile Delinquency: Extent, Causation (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Soc 435: Family In General (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Soc 475: Ideas And Developments (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Soc 475: Internationalism (Europe Relations With US) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Soc 475: Political Democracy (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Soc 475: Women - USSR + Germany (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Soc 483: Birth Control (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Soc 483: Economic Conditions (Before 1957) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Soc 483: Growing Unity - Economy (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Soc 483: Language (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Soc 483: Nationality - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Soc 483: Religion (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Soc 483: Religion - Germany (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Soc 483: Religion - USSR (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Soc 483: Unsorted (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Soc 487: Education: European vs. American (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Soc 573: Introductory Comments (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Press Clippings
  This is the largest series in the collection and contains one hundred ninety-one folders, arranged alphabetically. A partial listing of topics include: history, political and sociological issues around the world including England, Ireland, Germany, Pakistan, Japan, China, and Russia. Many of these articles appear to be taken from newspapers and magazines from the country of origin. Original folder titles were maintained including the vernacular of the period.
  - Africa (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Age: Increasing Concerns + New Attitudes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aged: Current Illustrative Material, Possible Danger In Social Security (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Alcoholism (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - American History (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annexation Phenomenon (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Articles: Europe: On Irish, On Russia Sputnik (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Articles On Europe Germany (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Asia: China (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Asia: India Pakistan (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Asia: Japan (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Asia: Middle East: Arab Countries - Israel, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Asia: Southeast: Indonesia, Indochina, etc… (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Belgium (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bibliographies: Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography on "Russia Since 1900" (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Birth Control: General (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Birth Control + Population Decline (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Birth Control: Pro Con Arguments In Western World: US, England, Europe (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Birth Control: Status Today (1960), Non Western World: Japan, India, China (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cities Zoning + Planning (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Decentralization Trends: Sub-urban, etc… (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Democracy: Army: Accusations, Character, Improvements (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Democracy: Congress - How functions: Relation to President [ Subservience], Relation To Official Party (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Democracy: Courts: Independence, Honesty, Fairness, Quality (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Democracy: Elections (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Democracy: Elections: National, State, Municipal, Electoral, How Conducted, Scandals, Accusations, Law 1946, Elections. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Democracy: Officials: Corruption, Arbitrariness, Inefficiency, Violence, Election, and Interference. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Democracy: Parties: General (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Democracy: Parties: ISMS (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Democracy: Parties: Minor Parties + Groups (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Democracy: Parties: PAN (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Democracy: Parties: PAN #2 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Democracy: Parties: PAN (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Democracy: Parties: PC (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Democracy: Parties: PP (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Democracy: Parties: PRI (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Democracy: Parties: PRI #21 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Democracy: Parties: UNS (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Democracy: President: Casiquismo, Relation To Registration, Great Powers (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Democracy: Public Opinion (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Democracy: Violence [Shootings, Beatings, Arrests…] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Diplomacy of WWI (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Divorce: Remedies (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - East Europe: USSR (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Education: International Europe (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Education: Mexico + Latin America (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - England, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - England: British Isles (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - English History (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - English History (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Europe, 1492 -1789 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Europe, 1815 -1914 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Europe: Bibliography, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Europe: England (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Europe: Films (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Europe: Frances (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Europe: General (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Europe In General: General Material, (Before 1950) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Europe In General: Philosophies (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Europe: Housing (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Europe: Ireland (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Europe: Southern + Eastern, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - European Economy Conditions + Projects (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - European Town: General Material On Europe's Problem + Culture (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Family: Children (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Family: Conflicts on Children (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - First Period of Decline of Kiev (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Food Supply: Increasing Yield Per Unit (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Policy (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - France, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - France: Descriptive Literature (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - France: Pictures, etc. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - French Revolutionary Period, 1789-1815 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Germany (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Germany, Before 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - History, 1789 -1821 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - History, 1821 -1854 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - History: 3 Presidents, 1928 -1934 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - History: Aleman, 1946 -1952 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - History: Ayila Camacho, 1940 -1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - History: Calles Period, 1924 -1928 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - History: Cardenas, 1934 -1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - History: Carranza Era, 1914 -1920 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - History: Constitution, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - History: Diaz Period, 1877 - 1910 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - History: General (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - History: General: Lopez Mateos: Summary, Statements, Presidential Addresses, Criticisms + Judgements, Mexico On Balance., 1958 - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - History: General: Ruiz Cortinez: Pros Cons, Mexico On Balance, 1952 - 1958 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - History: Juarez Period, 1854 - 1877 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - History: Madero, 1910 - 1913 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - History: Obregon, 1920 - 1924 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - History: Pre - Spanish (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - History: Revolution, 1910 To Present (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - History: Spanish Period (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Holland (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Holland, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Improvement Trends: Houston (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Improvement Trends: Specific American Cities (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - India - Remarriage (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - International Education - American College Programs (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - International: Student Exchange + Aids, Scholarships, Information Relating to Foreign Study (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Introductory: Food Lag + Other Dangers (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Introductory: New Books + Writings (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Introductory: Population Increase (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Italy (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Italy, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Italy, Before 1952 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Latin America (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Latin America (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Latin America: Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Mateos, Lopez (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Medieval History, 476 - 1492 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Medieval History, 476 - 1492 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mexicans In Our Cities (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mexicans In The United States (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mexico Capsule: Unsorted Material (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mexico: Writings Papers In Mexico (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Middle America: Caribbean - Central America, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nationalism (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nationalism + Race: USSR (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Negroes (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Negroes:, 1963 And Recent (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Negroes: Discrimination In General: South (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Negroes: Education: Education of Segregation (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Negroes: Education: Outlook For Solution Of School Integration Crisis, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Negroes: Employment Discrimination (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Negroes: Evidence Document: Better Treatment (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Negroes: Historical Background (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Negroes: Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Negroes: Racial Discrimination Outside US: England, South Africa, India, Japan (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Negroes: Trouble In the North: Housing, Schooling, Employment, etc… (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Negroes: White Tensions + Conflicts (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Overpopulation (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Pension: Public Private (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Pol Ideologies: Fascism (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Pol Ideologies: Nazism (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Pol Ideologies: USSR (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Politics + Crimes (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Race And Racism: Prejudice Discrimination: General (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Racism: Germany (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Resources: Africa (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Resources: Asia (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Resources: Australia (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Resources: Brazil, Argentina + Latin America Generally (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Resources: China (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Resources: Europe (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Resources: India + Pakistan (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Resources: Japan (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Resources: Latin America (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Resources: U.S. Agricultural: Meeting the Drought + Water Problems (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Resources: U.S. Agriculture: The Present (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Resources: U.S. General (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Resources: U.S.S.R: Agriculture (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Resources: Western Hemisphere: Canada + Latin America (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Russia, Since 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Scandinavia: Descriptive Literature (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Slums (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Social Security (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Southern Trade + Industrialism Resources Energy: International Economy - Cooperation + Mutuality (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Spain (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Descriptive Literature (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Specific Examples Of American Cities (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sweden (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Switzerland: Descriptive Literature (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Television (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Trade Industry: Capital Investments: Shortages, Difficulties, etc… (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Trade Industry: Foreign Aid (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Trade Industry: International Trade: Difficulties: Tariffs + Other Obstacles (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Turkey: Descriptive Literature (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - U.S.: Ideals (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - USSR, 1934 - 1935 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - USSR, 1937 - 1939 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - USSR, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - USSR, 1945 - 1947 - 1948 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - USSR, 1946 - 1956 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - USSR: Address + Articles (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - USSR: Agriculture (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - USSR: Industrial (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - USSR: Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - USSR: Political + General (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - USSR: Recent Material: Education, Science, Tension (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - USSR: Materials for Tasks, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - USSR: Trotskyism (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - USSR: Un-assorted Material, 1957 - 1958 - 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - USSR: Un-assorted Material, 1957 - 1958 - 1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - USSR: Un-assorted Material, 1957 - 1958 - 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - USSR: Un-assorted Material, 1959 - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - USSR: Un-assorted Material, 1959 - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Women: Immorality Drunkenness (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Index cards (Box 10, Folder 1)